仁鉄が打った｡
捜索を依頼された ﾎﾞｸたち➡
(新八)紅桜｡
万事屋が見たものは…｡
行方不明になった その刀の➡
あの人斬り似蔵だった｡
江戸一番の刀匠とうたわれた➡
その紅桜を使って
辻斬りをしている➡
人の魂を吸うという
恐ろしい妖刀｡
激しい戦いの末 瀕死の重傷を➡
負ってしまった 銀さん｡
"The Benizakura."
失踪した 桂さんを探しにいった➡
It was forged by, Jintetsu, the best swordsmith in Edo.
神楽ちゃんも戻ってこない｡
単身捜索を続ける ﾎﾞｸは➡
But it's said this feared "demon sword" sucks out people's souls.
港で 偽装された
一艘の船に たどり着く｡
一方 万事屋に現れた➡
We, the Odd Jobs Trio, were asked to find the missing sword.
鉄子が語ったのは➡
兄 鉄也と高杉一派が➡
機動兵器化された紅桜を使って➡
We witnessed Nizo the Butcher using Benizakura for random murder.
江戸を焦土と化そうとする➡
恐るべき計画だった｡
Gin-san was mortally wounded after an intense fight.
Kagura-chan, who went looking for the missing Katsura-san, hasn't returned.
I kept searching and found a camouflaged ship docked in port.
Moreover, Tetsuko visited the Odd Jobs to report that her brother, Tetsuya,
was working with Takasugi's group on a terrible plan
to use the Benizakura to turn Edo into an inferno.
[Revenge against Takasugi's group. The Anti-Foreigner Faction fleet assault.]
[Takasugi's plans for a coup d'etat... Can Gintoki stop it?]
I'm relieved.
(お妙)安心しました｡
(銀時)あ？
I was afraid you'd try to go out despite your injuries.
(お妙)
行くんじゃないかと思ったから｡
そんな体でも…｡
(銀時)ﾌﾝｯ｡
…そんな体で行っても
死んじゃいますもんね｡
You'd die if you went out in your condition.
そうだな…｡
You're right.
I feel sorry for that girl, but it can't be helped.
(お妙)あの女の子には 申し訳
ないけど しかたないですよね｡
…そうだな｡
...You're right.
銀さん｡
あ？
Gin-san.
Huh?
あんまり ﾑﾁｬをするのは
もう やめてくださいね…｡
Please don't overdo it.
銀さんが いなくなったら
新ちゃんも神楽ちゃんも➡
If you die, Shin-chan and Kagura-chan would be lost without you, Gin-san.
困りますから｡
…そうだな｡
...You're right.
昔は 銀さんも
いろいろ やんちゃ➡
Gin-san, you were pretty wild in your youth,
やってたようだけれども もう➡
but you've got to start acting your age now, you know?
そんなことする歳
じゃないですもんね｡
しつけえんだよ この野郎！
That's enough, damn it! I'm not going anywhere,
もう どこにも行かねえから
ちょっと ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣買ってこい！
so just go out and buy me JUMP!
お前 さっき
買ってきたの 赤ﾏﾙだぞ｡
The last one you bought was an Akamaru JUMP.
お母さんみてえな
間違いしてんじゃねえよ！
That's the kind of mistake my mom would make!
Yes, yes. I understand.
(お妙)はいはい わかりましたよ｡
♪♪～
…すまねえな｡
I'm sorry.
Watch it, moron!
(男)気をつけろ！ この野郎!!
♪♪～
[Wait at the swordsmith's. -Odd Jobs guy]
ｵﾚだって いい歳
こいて やんちゃ➡
I hate to behave like an impulsive punk at my age, but....
なんか やりたかねえ
けどよ… ん？ あっ｡
♪♪～
[This is my favorite umbrella. Please bring it back to me in one piece.]
Tsk... Troublesome woman...
ﾁｯ… かわいくねえ女｡
♪♪～
(お妙)ﾊﾞｶな人…｡
Stupid Man...
["The Sun Will Rise Again"]
(爆発音)
(ざわめき)
Is it the Shinsengumi? Don't tell me those Bukufu's dogs found out...
(浪士)真選組か!? まさか
幕府の犬にかぎつけられ…｡
(浪士)いや 違う… あれは｡
No, that's not it!
That's...!
♪♪～
(志士)高杉ぃぃ！
Takasugi!
You bastard!
ｷｻﾏ！ 志を同じくする➡
You're a samurai who has the same ambitions as us,
尽忠報国の士でありながら➡
but you killed Kotaro Katsura, the leader of the Rebel Factions.
我らが 攘夷志士の暁➡
桂 小太郎を
殺めた罪 許しがたし｡
That's unforgivable!!
(志士)我らは もう
共に歩む仲間ではない｡
We're not comrades anymore!
(志士)志の遠く離れた敵である｡
Our ambitions conflict so we're enemies now!
(志士)よって
ここに天誅をくださん｡
Now suffer the punishment of heaven!!
撃てぇっ！
(砲撃音)
(志士)どこ 狙ってんですか！
Where are you aiming?!
(志士)うわっ｡
Whoa!
(武市)なに!? 桂の仲間が｡
What?! Katsura's followers?!
(武市)すぐに 船を出す準備を｡
Prepare the ship for departure immediately.
このままでは… 上空
から 狙い撃ちにされ➡
If they get off a shot from above, we're finished!
撃沈されます｡
They came to avenge Katsura.
(また子)桂の敵討ち
って わけっすか…｡
似蔵め… 全部 ﾔﾂのせいっす｡
Nizo... This is all his fault.
(武市)それも あるでしょうが➡
It probably is. But it's more likely they found out about the Benizakura.
恐らく 紅桜の存在が
露見したと思われます｡
(武市)以前は過激な攘夷思想の
持ち主だった 桂も 昨今では➡
I heard that Katsura used to be an exclusionist rebel with radical ideas,
but these days, he's renounced extreme violence.
無用な争いを嫌う穏健派に
なっていた と聞きます…｡
(武市)亡き 桂になりかわり➡
I think they're here to destroy the Benizakura,
紅桜を殲滅し… 我々の➡
and thwart our plans on behalf of the late Katsura.
武装蜂起を阻むつもりかと…｡
…いや 先輩｡
No, Senpai.
(また子)案外 この娘が
連中の仲間で… この➡
It's possible this girl is one of their members
and this attack is just a diversion.
襲撃自体が ただの陽動と
いうことも ありえまっす｡
ともすれば この船に ﾈｽﾞﾐが➡
If that's the case, a rat may have snuck aboard this ship.
忍び込んでいるやもしれませんね｡
In any case, we can turn the tables on them.
どちらにせよ…
これを利用しない手はないです｡
(また子)はい 聞けぇ！ お前ら!!
Hey, listen up you rebels!
お前らの目的は読めた！
We know why you're here!
(また子)この娘っすね
なんやかんやで この➡
It's this girl, right?
We know you want to rescue her!
娘を助けたいのは…
痛いほど わかってるっす｡
(また子)そんなに ﾊﾞﾝﾊﾞﾝ撃って
この娘に当たっても知らない…｡
But if you keep shooting us you might accidentally hit her.
(砲撃音)
武市先輩！ 話が
違うじゃないっすか｡
Takechi-senpai, that's not what was supposed to happen!
My expectations were off. But their cannonball missed so I guess we're even.
予想が外れましたね… まぁ➡
砲弾も外れたから
よしとしましょう｡
外れてるのは ｱﾝﾀの頭のﾈｼﾞっすよ｡
No, the screws in your head are missing!
(神楽)ﾌﾟﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ… ﾊﾞｯｶじゃねえの｡
You guys are so stupid!
あんな連中と何にも
関係ないもんねぇ！
I have nothing to do with those guys!
You guessed wrong. How embarrassing!
勘違いしてやんの
ﾌﾟﾌﾟｯ 恥ずかしい…｡
What are you gloating about?
(また子)何 浮かれてんの!?
お前が一番 危機的状況なんだよ｡
You're the one in the most dangerous position.
げっ また！
(砲撃音)
Whoa! Incoming!
Hey, wait! What about me?!
(神楽)ちょ お前ら
そんな 無責任なぁ！
う… うわ!!
(爆発音)
ﾁｯ… 何の役にも
立たなかったっす｡
Tsk. She didn't prove useful at all.
あっ！
Sorry to keep you waiting, Kagura-chan!
(新八)お待たせ
新八!!
神楽ちゃん！
Shinpachi!
(似蔵)うっ… うぅ…｡
う…｡
(高杉)よぅ｡
Yo.
(高杉)お苦しみのところ
失礼するぜ｡
I hate to bother you when you're suffering.
お前のお客さんだ｡
But your guests have arrived.
いろいろ
派手に やってくれたらしいな｡
You really messed things up.
おかげで幕府とやりあう前に➡
Now thanks to you, I have to fight these annoying fools
面倒な連中と
やりあわなきゃ ならねえようだ｡
before we take on the Bakufu.
(高杉)桂 やったらしいな…｡
I heard you killed Katsura.
おまけに
銀時とも やりあったとか…➡
Moreover, you fought with Gintoki. You even used Tetsuya Murata.
わざわざ村田まで使って｡
んで？
立派なﾃﾞｰﾀは とれたのかい？
So? Were you able to collect any good data?
村田も さぞ お喜びだろう｡
Murata must be happy with it. He'd do anything to make his sword more deadly.
ﾔﾂは自分の剣を強くすることしか
考えてねえからな｡
ﾌｯ… ｱﾝﾀは どうなんだい？
Humph... What about you?
(似蔵)昔の同士が
簡単にやられちまって➡
Your old chum was killed so easily
悲しんでいるのかな？
so you're feeling sad...
(似蔵)それとも…｡
Or...
ほぅ…｡
That's an impressive arm you're growing there.
(高杉)すいぶんと立派な腕が
生えたじゃねえか｡
I'm glad you two get along so well together. You've literally become one.
仲よくやってるようで安心したよ｡
文字どおり 一心同体ってﾔﾂか｡
さっさと片づけてこい｡
Hurry up and go kill them.
If you wipe them out, I'll forget this matter.
(高杉)あれ全部 潰してきたら➡
今回の件は不問にしてやらあ｡
(高杉)どのみち連中とは➡
I knew it would eventually come to this.
いずれ
こうなっていただろうしな｡
それから…➡
And...
二度と ｵﾚたちを
同士なんて呼び方するんじゃねえ｡
Don't ever call Gintoki my chum again.
そんな 甘っちょろいもんじゃ
ねえんだよ ｵﾚたちは｡
There're no warm feelings between us anymore.
次言ったら
ｿｲﾂごと ぶった斬るぜ｡
Say it again and I'll cut right through you and that weird sword.
《今のは
本気で斬るつもりだったね…》
...He was seriously going to kill me...
んご～っ!!
Who are you?!
何者っすか！ おい 答えるっす!!
Hey!
Answer me!
また子さん 走ることに
集中したほうが よさそうですよ｡
Matako-san, we'd better focus on running, or we'll end up like that guy!
でないと ああなりま… うっ！
No! I'm falling!
ﾀﾞﾒ！ もう落ちる！
Kagura-chan, I came here to save you. But now I need you to save me instead.
神楽ちゃん
助けにきといて なんだけど➡
助けてぇ!!
(神楽)そりゃねえぜ ぱっつぁん｡
This can't be happening, Pa-chan.
[Note: Kagura imitates Shinpachi's way of nicknaming her Kagura-chan by calling him Pa-chan]
のんきでいいな ﾃﾒｴはよ～！
How can you be so easy-going right now?!
新八 ｱﾀｼ
こんな所までﾂﾞﾗ捜しにきたけど➡
Shinpachi, I came all the way over here to find Zura, but I failed.
やっぱり見つからなかったね
ﾂﾞﾗは どうなったｱﾙか？
What happened to Zura? Where's Gin-chan? Why is Gin-chan not here?
銀ちゃんは？
なんで銀ちゃんいないの？
う…｡
新八？
Shinpachi...
(爆発音)
うわぁ！ うっ…｡
あっ！
し… 新八…｡
Shi-Shinpachi!
わぁ！
神楽ちゃん！
Kagura-chan!
♪♪～
(志士)なんじゃ ありゃ…？
What's that?
That's Nizo! Nizo the Butcher!!
あれは似蔵！ 人斬り似蔵!!
たった１人で 何をするつもりだ！
What is he going to do all by himself?!
Shoot him!
撃て!! 撃ち落としてしまえ！
Blast him out of the sky!!
♪♪～
うおぉぉ!!
((高杉:おい｡
Hey...
Does killing such small fry satisfy you?
そんな小せえもん壊して
満足か？))
(砲撃音)
壊してやるよ 何もかも！
I'll destroy everything!
はぁぁ!!
きぇぇい!!
うぉぉぉ～！
((どうせ壊すなら どうだ一緒に))
If you want to destroy something, why don't we...
んんん～!!
((高杉:世界をぶっ壊しに
いかねえか？))
destroy the world?
(爆発音)
(志士)か 刀１本で…｡
He did that with just one sword...
化け物か…｡
Is he a monster?!
♪♪～
(鉄矢)う～ん…｡
うっ…｡
うぅ… ｸｯ…！
Shinpachi!
新八… あっ！
ああっ！
え… ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ！
Elizabeth!
You've made it all the way up here!
こんな所まで来てくれたんだね！
[I have to take care of something here.]
(神楽/新八)あっ！
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ～！
Elizabeth!
おいおい…｡
Hey, hey. When did this place become a costume party?
いつのまに仮装ﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰ会場に
なったんだ？ ここは｡
This is no place for kids.
ｶﾞｷが来て いいところじゃねえよ｡
≪ｶﾞｷじゃない…｡
I'm no kid.
《高杉:このにおい…》
This smell...
(桂)桂だ！
I'm Katsura.
(砲撃音)
(志士)何をしている！
早く撃墜せんか!!
What are you doing?! Shoot him down!
(志士)ﾀﾞﾒです！ 動きが速いし
目標が小さすぎます!!
We can't! He's moving so fast and the target is too small!
ええい！
たった一人に なんてｻﾞﾏだ!!
Come on, why are we having trouble with just one man?!
落とせ！ 落とせ～!!
Shoot him down! Shoot him down!
Go, Benizakura!
(似蔵)いけ～ 紅桜!!
(ざわめき)
Attention No. 3 fleet, disable steering! Everyone, retreat! Everyone, retreat!
(志士)三番艦 操舵不能！
総員 待避せよ 総員 待避せよ!!
ｸｸｸｯ… どうだい？
この紅桜とともに➡
How's that?
I've come to this stupid world for nothing but with Benizakura, I'll destroy everything.
くだらねえ世の中すべてを
無に返してやるよ！
すべてを壊してやるよ！
ｸｸｸｯ… ﾊﾊﾊｯ…！
ぐっ… これは！
This is...
ぐぅっ… こんなときに…｡
Why now...?
♪♪～
Hey, hey, hey, hey. It looks like it's already started.
おいおい おいおい…
何かもう おっ始まってやがらぁ！
ｵﾚたちが行く前に
ｶﾀつくんじゃねえの？ おい｡
It's liable to be over before we get there.
使い込んだ紅桜は ひと振りで
戦艦十隻の戦闘力を有する｡
One good swing with Benizakura has the same fighting power as 10 warships.
あんなもので止めるのは ﾑﾘだ｡
It's impossible for them to stop it.
規模が でかすぎて
しっくりこねえよ…｡
I don't get it.
もっと身近なもので
例えてくれる？
Can you compare it to something I'm more familiar with?
Its battle strength is equivalent to 1,000 mothers if their boobs were missiles.
ｵｯﾊﾟｲがﾐｻｲﾙの
お母さん1,000人分の戦闘力だ｡
そんなの もう
お母さんじゃねえよ！
Those aren't mothers!
A mother is supposed to be nagging, despotic, one-sided, unhearing of others, and...
お母さんってのはな
なんか口うるさくて横暴で➡
一方的で
人の話なんか聞かないで…｡
あれ？ これ ﾐｻｲﾙ撃っても
おかしくなくない？
Huh?!
Then it's not surprising that she can shoot missiles...
ｺｲﾂを…｡
ん？
Take this...
What's this?
なに？ これ｡
私が打った刀だ｡
It's the sword I forged.
木刀では
紅桜と戦えない… 使え！
You can't defeat Benizakura with that wooden sword of yours. Use that.
The blade looks nice, but the hand guard looks like a pile of poo...
刀はいいけど なに？ これ｡
この鍔の装飾… ｳﾝ…｡
うっ！
ぐおぉ… ﾃﾒｴ 何しやがんだ!?
What the hell are you doing?!
(鉄子)ｳﾝｺじゃない！
とぐろを巻いた龍だ!!
It's not poop! It's a coiled dragon.
Hey, you! You said "poop" even before I finished saying "poop."
ﾃﾒｴ！ ｵﾚがｳﾝｺと言い切る前に
ｳﾝｺと言ったということは➡
自分でも 薄々ｳﾝｺと
思っている証拠じゃねえか！
That means you were aware it looks like poop, right?!
(騒ぎ声)
Elizabeth-sama!
Elizabeth-san!!
(志士)ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさん…｡
(志士)船の用意ができました｡
The ship is ready.
But are you really sure you should go?
(志士)
しかし ﾎﾝﾄに行くんですか!?
(志士)すでに こちらの船は
二隻も落とされているんですよ｡
They've already destroyed two of our ships!
(志士)ろくな重火器も
積んでおらんのに！
And our ship is not capable of loading enough heavy armaments.
(志士)いったい ﾔﾂら どんな
恐ろしい兵器を所有しているか｡
I wonder what kind of terrifying weapons they have.
[I have to save those kids. If they die, I won't be able to face Katsura-san.]
(志士)顔向けも何も
桂さんは もう…｡
You say you won't be able to face him, but Katsura-san is already...
♪♪～
[I sense a familiar presence aboard that ship.]
Elizabeth-san, don't tell me...!
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさん まさか!?
(志士)それって ｳｿ？ ﾏｼﾞで!?
You mean... Can it be?!
こうしちゃいられねえ！
早く あの船に!!
We can't just stand around!
Hurry, head to the ship!
(志士)ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさんの勘は
よく当たるんだ！
Elizabeth-san's hunches often prove right.
(志士)この間も ｵﾚ 競馬で
本命 買おうとしたんだけど➡
Just the other day, I was at the horse races...
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさんがね…｡
(また子)晋助様～！
Shinsuke-sama!
晋助様！ しっかり!! 晋助様～！
Shinsuke-sama! Come on, Shinsuke-sama!
(武市)ほぅ…
これは 意外な人と お会いする｡
Oh... I didn't expect to see you here.
(武市)こんなところで
死者と対面できるとは｡
I didn't expect to meet a dead man.
ｳｿ!?
No way...
桂さん！
Katsura-san!
この世に未練があったものでな…
よみがえってきたのさ｡
I had unfinished business so I returned from the underworld.
かつての仲間に
斬られたとあっては➡
I can't rest in peace after being slain by a comrade.
死んでも死にきれぬというもの｡
(桂)なぁ？ 高杉｡
お前も そうだろう…｡
Right, Takasugi? Know what I mean?
ｸｸｸｯ… 仲間ねぇ…｡
A comrade...
まだ
そう思ってくれていたとは➡
I didn't know you still thought of us that way.
ありがた迷惑な話だ｡
But that's an unwelcome thought.
You still carry that?
まだ そんなものを持っていたか｡
(桂)お互い ﾊﾞｶらしい…｡
I guess we're both fools.
(高杉)お前も ｿｲﾂのおかげで
紅桜から守られたってわけかい？
So that's what saved you from the Benizakura.
(高杉)思い出は
大切にするもんだねぇ｡
It's good to cherish old memories.
No, your henchman's incompetence saved me.
(桂)いや ｷｻﾏの
無能な部下のおかげさ｡
よほど興奮していたらしい｡
He was too eager.
ろくに確認もせずに
髪だけ刈り取って去っていった｡
He took my hair, but he left without making sure I was dead. Some butcher.
大した人斬りだ…｡
You're good at running away and now you're getting better at playing possum.
逃げ回るだけじゃなく➡
死んだふりまで
うまくなったらしい｡
で…
わざわざ 復讐に来たわけかい？
So, have you come all this way for revenge?
ﾔﾂを差し向けたのは ｵﾚだと？
Do you think I was the one who sent him?
あれが ｷｻﾏの差し金だろうが
ﾔﾂの独断だろうが関係ない｡
I don't care if you sent him or if it was his own decision.
だが お前の
やろうとしていること➡
But I know what you're planning and I can't let you do it.
黙って見過ごすわけにもいくまい｡
(爆発音)
ｷｻﾏの野望…
悪いが 海に消えてもらおう｡
I'm sending your ambitions to the bottom of the sea.
(ざわめき)
何が起きている？
What's going on?!
The factory! The Benizakura!
(浪士)工場が！ 紅桜が!!
Katsura!
桂～！
You bastard! You'll never get off this ship alive!
(浪士)ｷｻﾏ！
生きて帰れると思うな!!
江戸の夜明けを この目で
見るまでは 死ぬわけにはいかん｡
Until I see the fall of Edo,
I can't die.
If Edo is awakened by barbarians like you guys, it would be repulsive.
ｷｻﾏら野蛮な輩に
揺り起こされたのでは➡
江戸も寝覚めが悪かろうて｡
明日を見ずして眠るがいい！
So I'll kill you before the morning sun rises.
(神楽)眠るのは ﾃﾒｴだ！
The person who's gonna get killed is...
...you!
We were worried sick about you!
ﾃﾒｴ…
人に さんざん心配かけといて➡
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽの中に入ってただ!?
And you were hiding inside Elizabeth?!
ふざけんのも大概にしろ～！
Take that, you inconsiderate jerk!!
いつから
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽん中 入ってた!? あん！
Since when were you inside Elizabeth, anyway?
How long have you been playing us?
いつから ｵﾚたちを騙してた!?
Hey, wait. Can't we talk about this later?
ちょ… 待て！ 今 そういうことを
言ってる場合じゃないだろう！
Look! These guys are about to attack us!
ほら 見て！ 今にも
襲いかかってきそうな雰囲気だよ｡
Shut up! We're about to attack you!
うるせえんだよ!! こっちも
襲いかかりそうな雰囲気!!
待て 落ち着け！
Wait! Calm down.
It wasn't fair that I didn't tell you anything. I apologize.
何も 知らせなかったのは
悪かった｡ 謝る！
(桂)今回の件は➡
I thought the enemy was just after me.
敵が ｵﾚ個人を
標的に動いていると 思ったゆえ➡
敵の内情を探るにも➡
So I thought it would be best if I made my enemy think I was dead.
ｵﾚは 死んでいることに
しておいたほうが➡
動きやすいと考え
何も 知らせなんだ…！
That's why I didn't tell you anything.
(桂)何より ｵﾚ個人の問題に➡
And on top of that, I didn't want to get the others involved in my personal problems.
他人を巻き込むのは
不本意だったしな｡
That's why I disguised myself as...
(桂)ゆえに こうして 変装して…｡
But why as Elizabeth?!
(２人)
だから なんで ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽなんだ～!!
We can't get near him! He's a whirlwind of death!
近寄れねえ… まるで ｽｷが ねえ！
なに やってんすか～！
(武市)あれは…｡
What are you doing?!
That's...
おい あれ… なんか こっちに…｡
Hey, that...looks like it's coming this way.
おわたっ！
(２人)んっ？
(浪士たち)うわぁぁ～っ!!
(爆発音)
The ship rammed us! What are they doing?!
(浪士)
船が 突っ込んできやがった！
(浪士)なんて ﾏﾈを！
(志士たち)うわぁぁ～っ!!
Takasugi! You ain't getting away with this!!
(志士)高杉～！
ｷｻﾏの思いどおりには させん!!
全員 たたき斬るっす～!!
Tsk! Cut them down!!
♪♪～
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ… みんな…｡
Elizabeth... You guys...
[I can't stand this.]
(志士)すみません 桂さん｡
いかなることが あろうと➡
I'm sorry, Katsura-san.
You ordered us not to take action under any circumstances.
勝手に 兵を動かすな と
言われておきながら➡
But when we heard you were in trouble, we had to do something!
桂さんに 変事ありき と聞き
居ても立ってもいられず…！
We couldn't believe you'd been killed and when we heard you were here...
(志士)
このようなことで 桂さんが➡
死ぬわけがないと
信じておりましたが➡
最後の最後で 我々は…｡
Stop it.
やめてくれ…｡
There's no way I can blame you when you have such apologetic looks on your faces.
そんな顔で謝る お前たちを
叱れるわけもない｡
In fact, I'm the one who should apologize for keeping everyone in the dark.
[Shut up and fight!]
(桂)それに 謝らなければ
ならぬのは ｵﾚのほうだ｡
(桂)なんの連絡も せずに…｡
Katsura-san, you were trying to stop them all by yourself, weren't you?
(志士)桂さん あなた１人で
止めるつもりだったんでしょう!?
You were trying to convince them to save your one-time comrade,
(志士)かつての仲間である
高杉を救おうと➡
騒ぎを広めずに １人 説得に
いくつもりだったんでしょう！
Takasugi, without making a big deal out of it, right?
Yet we attacked and ruined your plan!
それを 我々は
このように騒ぎ立て➡
Now the rift between our group and Takasugi's is even wider! So...
高杉一派との亀裂を
完全なものに してしまった！
これでは もう…｡
言うな｡
That's not true.
ﾔﾂとは いずれ
こうなっていたさ…｡ んっ？
Something like this was bound to happen sooner or later anyways.
[We'll take care of this, so hurry up and go.]
[It's not over yet.]
Elizabeth...
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ…｡
[And please don't disappear again, okay?]
…すまぬ！
Sorry...
させるか～!!
We can't let you go!
Get out of my way!
そこを どけ～!!
お前ら…!?
You guys!
We'll fight by your side to the bitter end to stop these guys!
ここまで来たら
最後まで つきあいますからね！
Zura! You better buy me some snacks when we get back!
ﾂﾞﾗ～！
ﾃﾒｴ 帰ったら なんか おごるｱﾙ！
お前ら…｡
You guys...
(銃声)
晋助様のところへは
行かせないっす！
We won't let you get to Shinsuke-sama.
I'm afraid even a feminist must sometimes become a demon.
悪いが ﾌｪﾐﾆｽﾄといえど
鬼になることも あります｡
When my meticulous plans get ruined I get really angry, damn it.
綿密に立てた計画
これを 台なしにされるのが➡
いちばん 腹が立つ
こんちきしょ～｡
Tsk.
ﾁｯ！ あっ…!?
ﾂﾞﾗ… 私 酢こんぶ１年分と➡
Zura... I want a year's supply of pickled seaweed
and the entire series of "Wataru seken wa onishikaine konoyaro" on DVD.
『渡る世間は 鬼しかいねえ
この野郎』ＤＶＤ全巻ね｡
Ah, and food for Sadaharu.
あっ！ あと 定春のｴｻ｡
I want Otsu-chan's new album and photo book and
ﾎﾞｸ お通ちゃんのﾆｭｰｱﾙﾊﾞﾑと
写真集と➡
ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭｱｲｽ100個 お願いします｡
100 Baagen-Dash ice creams, please.
Ah, 1,000.
あっ… やっぱ 1,000個！
(神楽)あっ ずるいね！
Hey, that's not fair! Then I want ten years' worth of pickled seaweed!
(神楽)じゃあ 私も
酢こんぶ 10年分！
おい 何を…！
(神楽/新八)早く行け ﾎﾞｹ～!!
Hey, what's with you two...
Hurry up and go, idiot!
待て!!
お前たちに 何か あったら➡
Wait! If something happens to you guys, how will I ever face Gintoki?!
ｵﾚは 銀時に 合わす顔がない！
Are you kidding?!
なに 言ってるｱﾙか～！
(２人)たぁぁ～っ!!
Just show him that freaky hairdo of yours and make him laugh!
その ﾍﾝﾃｺな髪型 見せて
笑ってもらえ～!!
I can't read you... You two are the only odd guys on this ship.
(武市)読めませんね…｡
(武市)この船に あって
あなたたちだけが 異質｡
You're neither exclusionist samurai nor Katsura's rebel cronies.
攘夷浪士でもなければ
桂の 配下の者でもない様子｡
もちろん 私たちの味方でもない｡
And you're obviously not with us.
What?! Who in the hell are you?!
なんなんすか お前ら！
いったい 何者なんすか!?
何が 目的すか！
What's your deal?
Who sent you, anyway?!
(また子)いったい
誰の 回し者すか!?
♪♪～
宇宙一 ﾊﾞｶな侍だ｡ この野郎｡
Well, if it isn't the dumbest samurai in the universe, you bastard.
♪♪～
[GINTOKI VS]
[BENIZAKURA and NIZO]
[TAKASUGI LAMENTS]
[KATSURA'S ASPIRATIONS]
[WATCH CAREFULLY]
[The next episode... "On A Moonless Night, Insects Are Drawn To The Light."]
[Tetsuya recalls his father's words. Can Tetsuko save her brother?]
[It's the climax of the Benizakura arc!! How will the battle end?!]